hey guys this looks like a fun one it
says find the area of the blue rectangle
and the rectangle is twice as wide as it
is tall and it hits the semicircle in
these various places if you guys want to
try this on your own pause it right now
cuz I'm going to solve it in 3 2 1 first
let's connect this point to this point
and I want to focus on this triangle
right here first off it's a right
triangle because this is a rectangle and
second it's isos because these two sides
are congruent that means it's a 45 4590
triangle and then since this angle is 45
we now know this angle this plus this is
a linear pair which means they have to
add to 180° so this angle will be
135° next let's finish up the circle and
I want to focus on this
135° this is called an inscribed angle
and if we look at it it's cutting the
circle into two parts this red Arc and
this blue arc a cool property about
inscribed angles is they are exactly
half of the arc that they subtend so
this red Arc is going to be double the
135 de so it'll be 270° and then since
the red Arc is 270° that leaves us 90°
for the blue arc for the next step let's
draw this radius here and this radius
here and let's focus on this 90° Arc
this angle right here is called a
central angle and central angles are
equal to the subtended arcs so this is
going to be a 90° angle and we usually
notate that as a box in the corner and
since both of these are radi they both
have a length of five so if we connect
this here we have another isoceles right
triangle if we use a shortcut for 45
4590 triangles we can see this green
side is equal to 5 < tk2 and here's the
steps of the Pythagorean theorem to
verify it and we just did all of this
work just so we could get this green
length right here we can go back to here
and let's bring back our rectangle
looking at our rectangle if we call the
shorter side x this longer side is going
to be 2X and we have formed another
right triangle let's focus on that and
now we can do Pythagorean theorem to
solve for x we have x^2 + 2x^2 = 5 <
tk22 we can bring down the x^2 and then
this squar will go to both the 2 and the
X and this two will go to both the 5 and
the square root so we have x^2 + 4 x^2 =
25 * 2 x^2 + 4x^2 is equal to 5 x^2 and
25 * 2 is equal to 50 after we divide
both sides by 5 we get x^2 is equal to
10 and after we square root both sides
we get X is equal to the squ < TK of 10
and now we know the shorter side of the
rectangle this x can change into < TK 10
and this 2x can change into 2un 10 and
now we can find the area of the
rectangle it's equal to base time height
where the base is equal to 2un 10 and
the height is equal to < TK 10 and
that's equal to 2 * 10 which is equal to
20 let's give it a label of square units
and put a box around it the area of the
blue rectangle is 20 square units how
exciting